Chapter 38
Memory transcription subject:

Governor Tarva,
Venlil Republic

Date [Standardized human time]:
October 6, 2136

There was a heaviness in my heart, as the four diplomats were ushered into the briefing room. The Mazic had been creating quite the scene outside, accusing his human hosts of kidnapping Laulo. Apparently, no amount of tact could prevent that; the uplift's disappearance was noted within minutes. President Cupo's dramatic theories, that the predators intended to poke and prod every diplomat, were generating panic among the others.

That meant we had to brief everyone, about the sabotage and the missing craft. The information needed to be turned over to the media as soon as possible too, since Cupo's outburst occurred in front of live cameras. How could we persuade such a paranoid individual? His mind longed to believe that humanity was up to something.

I wasn't sure how much of this briefing the Sivkit would remember, given that she was drugged with a light sedative. The Mazic, who had been quite gentle with Axsely, had to carry her into the room. The humans couldn't breathe without spooking the fluffy representative. Noah had accused the Sivkit Grand Herd of having a poor choice of personnel, and I'd begun to agree.

I should order her to return home, and request that the Herd send someone else. With behavior like this, it's impossible to establish any relations with her species.

Tossa was oddly quiet, and her gaze darted across the waiting predators. Despite her disdain for uplifts, her snooty attitude slipped when Laulo disappeared from their ranks. The Nevok had been trying to hawk her planet's refined metals and microchips to any Terran that would listen, but now, that interest had subsided.

Even Chauson looked curious at why the Yotul had vanished from their ranks, though he had more of an inkling what was going on. We had told him, in no uncertain terms, that someone on the ship could be involved. A scientist of the Zurulian's intellect might put the pieces together.

"I knew from the beginning that we couldn't trust you predators!" Cupo spat, as he took a seat on the floor. "You were just waiting to get us here to turn on us."

Chauson's whiskers twitched. "You should wait to hear what they're going to tell you, before you start with that nonsense. It's not what you think."

"Wait, you know? So Tarva and Noah have been selecting who to spin their yarns with. Who to hide things from," Tossa growled.

The Mazic president flared his trunk. "Half the shit that comes out of a human's mouth is a lie! Who knows why they want to manipulate us, but I bet it's about control. All their species has shown they care about is power!"

The UN diplomats fidgeted with their visors, clearly uncomfortable with the accusatory rhetoric. This couldn't have been their expectation when they greeted the landing party. I winced, as I saw the anger on the Terran generals' faces. They lacked the poise and the patience of their diplomatic counterparts; it was tough for them to shrug off insults.

"You know what: fuck the Federation. You can fuck right back off to your ship," General Zhao stood from his chair, and leaned across the table toward the Mazic president. "All you care about is where a person's eyes are on their head."

General Jones reclined in her seat. "And these are the 'friendly' species, Zhao. Who needs enemies, with friends like these?"

Axsely's chest was wracked with sobs, as the primates' tone escalated. The military humans shifted their annoyance to the sniveling animal. Their binocular eyes smoldered with indignation; the generals' tolerance for predator bigotry had been tested for the last time.

"And you, with the white pelt...you can't even look at us! Why are you here?" the Chinese general spat.

Jones bared her teeth, intentionally pointing them at the Sivkit. "Get a grip. You're embarrassing your race."

To be honest, if the brunt of a human's anger was directed at me, it would make me clam up too. When their jaw muscles were clenched, it showcased their flesh-tearing bite force. The lack of fur made the protruding bones and bulging veins more obvious; translucent skin confined the rage bubbling beneath the surface.

I can tell they're in control, but I don't think any other alien can.

"THAT IS ENOUGH! All of you are acting like children!" I screeched. "Let's agree that we've all messed up, in one way or another. We shared our information with Chauson, because he's the only one not looking for an excuse to spout predator nonsense. You lot just proved my point."

Noah squeezed my paw under the table. "Also, you guys tend to freak out at the slightest sign of danger. It was hard enough to keep everyone calm on the ship."

The Nevok diplomat sighed. "You get one chance to explain yourselves. The truth."

"Anti-human plotters in the Federation tried to kill us all with a cooling shaft malfunction. Recel's ship is missing, probably for the same reason," I replied.

"We're trying to figure out who's responsible, and hold them accountable," Noah added.

Tossa snorted. "And you think it's little, primitive Laulo?!"

The Terran ambassador tensed beside me; clearly, recent events hadn't stopped his defensive reaction to any "primitive" jabs. I gave Noah a look that warned him not to interfere. He swallowed hard, and inhaled a series of deep breaths.

This was not the time for him to give the Nevok an earful. Especially when she was the most level-headed person here, not named Chauson.

I offered a non-committal tail swish. "We're suspicious enough to ask questions."

It was plain to see from the representatives' faces that they were worried about how those questions were being asked. I swiped a few buttons on my holopad, and cast the security feed of the cell to the projector. The marsupial was seated alone on a bench, with his head in his paws. It was the predators' suggestion, to let him wait for awhile; to "give him time to marinate", was their phrase.

I didn't like that wording. But as long as the humans didn't suggest physical harm, I was happy to let them try out their techniques.

The feisty uplift raised his head, and stared at the camera. "I know you're listening, Ambassador Noah! I can see that red light blinking. I want to talk."

"Too bad. I don't," the astronaut muttered to himself.

The Mazic president settled down, once he saw the Yotul in pristine condition. I was surprised that he hadn't suggested that humanity could have staged the sabotage. Cupo was a strange case, and it was tough to pinpoint what he hoped to gain from diplomacy. Telling the Terran military, to their faces, that he thought all humans avaricious liars; that could only stem from remarkable disdain.

The fact that the leader came himself could be chalked up to an attempt at honorability. Cupo didn't want anyone else to die, for what he believed was a foolish gamble. Was it simply a desperation play, like he told Noah? I didn't know if he'd ever see humanity as anything more than predators.

General Jones tapped her earpiece. "Governor. A United Nations scout ship recovered a data buoy within the search perimeter. Almost missed it on sensors."

My ears perked up. Standard Federation vessels were equipped with two data buoys, which could be ejected if a ship was in distress. They contained information about a ship's function, and could be encoded with a message from the captain.

The buoy emitted a distress signal for a week, or as long as any nearby starlight replenished its power. Common scenarios for their usage included emergency landings, mechanical failures, or after sustaining damage in battle. It could offer insight to a vessel's fate, or point rescuers in the right direction.

I was uncertain whether to view a buoy's deployment as a positive, or a negative sign. It meant that the ship had incurred trouble, but it also meant Recel had been aware of the problem before a drive meltdown. Maybe they were in the process of mending considerable damage; all that mattered was whether they were alive.

"Alright. Was your team able to extract the data?" I asked.

"Yes. There appears to be a short video log included." Jones scrolled through the file archives, and tapped the mentioned item. "Shall I clear these interlopers out, so we can review what it says in private?"

My ears flattened against my head. "They're not 'interlopers.' At some point, we have to start acting like friends. I'm counting on humanity to take the first step."

I muted the feed from Laulo's cell, and moved that window into background processing. The American general frowned, as I gestured to the projector. Her gaze drifted to the skeptical Mazic; that first impression didn't make her eager to share intelligence. There was no telling what was on the video file, and it might not take much for such individuals to jump to conclusions.

A smog-filled cabin was depicted on the projector, with a delirious Kolshian at the helm. Recel dabbed a damp rag against his forehead; the internal temperature must be sweltering. The smoke was so thick, that gray tendrils seemed to curl around the Federation officer's form. His orange eyes were listing and unfocused.

I glimpsed a few Federation diplomats behind him; all were wearing vac suits to avoid the toxins. That would only be good while the half-day's oxygen supply lasted. Upon closer inspection, Recel had set a helmet down, out of the camera's focus. He must've taken it off so that he could be seen and heard on the recording.

"This is Recel of the Kolshian Commonwealth. A few hours ago, we noticed signs of a fire in the warp drive compartment. With the core ablaze, repairs are impossible." The officer burst into a coughing fit, and paused to catch his breath. "Emergency shutdown has been unsuccessful. Once it reaches a certain temperature, it's going to go off like a bomb."

As panicked as Recel had been around humans, his tranquility in the face of impending death was remarkable. I don't know how he'd kept the diplomats calm, or why they hardly reacted to those words. It helped that their ship didn't have a predator around, to add fuel to instinctual fear. Still, perhaps we just couldn't hear their cries from beneath the suits?

The Kolshian pilot grimaced. "I know we have mere hours, at most, but I'm at peace with my death. I spent my final days seeking the first real chance the Federation's had at ending the war, in my lifetime. Isn't that a beautiful thought?"

Water swelled in my eyes, as the finality of their predicament sank in. Recel's contributions to galactic peace were monumental, and rarely received full acknowledgment. When push came to shove, he found the courage to support humanity. It was his belief in diplomacy, encouraging us to attend the summit, that led Noah to speak to the Federation.

If it weren't for that heroic veteran, it would still be the two of us against the galaxy. Sovlin's actions could've been the catalyst for war. Humanity would've never seized the opportunity to voice their side of the story, or opened themselves up to new partners.

Recel might be the person who saved Earth. Who deserves as much credit as my dear Noah, I mused.

"There are some people who want to silence my version of events, regarding the torture of a human prisoner. I want it known that all I regret is that I didn't act sooner," he sputtered. "That I never had the courage to check in on Marcel, and apologize for my part in it. I hope he's doing well."

The Kolshian could hardly speak between coughing outbursts; his eyelids fluttered with exhaustion. He huddled over the console, and rested a grasper over the send button. The lack of clean oxygen had pushed him to the brink of unconsciousness.

Recel gritted his teeth. "Humans...if you see this, I remember what your leader said, about desiring co-existence. I hope people give you a chance, and that you won't lose faith. The things you endure would be too much, for any other species, but you're not them.

You're strong. You're predators. Maybe that is a good thing."

The Terran ambassador's mouth was agape with horror, as we observed Recel paw at his throat. This was someone we had traveled with for days, who offered his unique perspective on Federation history. It wasn't all that long ago the Kolshian greeted us in the hangar bay, and thanked Noah for reminding him what courage felt like.

"Agh...time's up," Recel whined, in a pained voice. "Kick some Arxur ass for me, humans. Leave a little less ugly in the galaxy. I have faith in you...."

The transmission cut out with a final beep, and was replaced by a grim static. The Federation diplomats looked aghast at what we just witnessed; even Axsely was showing signs of lucidity. The Terran generals dropped their scowls, and bowed their heads in a solemn display of grief. There was something sobering about a person's last words.

"We have to help them!" Cupo spat. "Send a ship."

Ambassador Noah nodded. "I will fly it myself if I have to. Those are our allies, and they're in trouble."

General Jones' lips curved down. "This video is time-stamped three days ago. There's no vessels on sensors. Only a few stray energy readings, which suggests..."

The only trace we'd find of the occupants was their atoms scattered across local space. Humanity's first interactions with those six species, would be the unenviable task of explaining how their diplomats died. I didn't know how we would convince their leadership not to fault the predators.

Condolences and words might not cut it. We need concrete proof.

The words the Krakotl uttered, that anyone who stood with humanity was dead to them, lingered in my ears. It was difficult for me to process that parties in the Federation would murder civilians, for the crime of speaking to predators. I wouldn't blame our new allies for not wanting to believe it was their long-standing friends.

My claws flung the prison surveillance back onto the projector; I was trembling with outrage. A taped confession would be a start, even if others accused us of coercion.

"Forget waiting." I switched on the intercom function, and leaned into my holopad. "Why did you betray us, Laulo? Why?"

The Yotul glanced up with a hopeful expression. "I'm so sorry. Saving our shuttle seemed like enough to spark gratitude. I just wanted to impress Noah, so humanity wouldn't discard us...like everyone else."

A chorus of gasps echoed from our Federation contingent. The predator generals looked mystified by his rationale, and their eyes narrowed to intimidating slits. None of us expected such a straightforward confession, especially when I was hoping we'd pegged the marsupial wrong.

"Impress me? You killed Recel, and almost killed us!" Noah snarled over my shoulder. "You're a homicidal psychopath!"

Laulo blinked. "What? Were you not listening to what I said before? I...I didn't do it. I just saw who did, and used the opportunity to, um, prove myself."

The human squinted. "Why should we believe that? Why wouldn't you come forward straight away?"

Murmurs of agreement came from the alien diplomats. It was bizarre to see the Mazic nodding along to a Terran argument, but it was natural to suspect the Yotul's claim. On one paw, it seemed like a lousy attempt to dodge responsibility. On the other, it made more sense than an uplift plotting a complex, technological scheme.

"The Takkan representative saw them too, and tried to intervene. Didn't you wonder why one friendly species never made it to the shuttle?" Laulo hissed. "Besides, we were on their territory! If I spoke up sooner, we would've never left Aafa."

Confusion stirred in my chest. "You're saying it was..."

The uplift swished his tail. "The Kolshians wanted the human ambassador, and his friends, dead. Not me. Who would have unfettered access to the shuttles? Who planned the whole trip, and saw Recel as a loose end?"

I fell back on my haunches, stunned to silence. Those words synced with the facts a little too perfectly. If Laulo was telling the truth, a touch-DNA sweep by the core should corroborate it. However, it didn't add up, why an influential species would grant humanity a public audience and seek a military alliance, only to kill us.

Was it even possible for our predators to track down a Kolshian official, and demand answers? Chief Nikonus was secure, at the heart of Federation territory. As much as I wanted to avenge the fallen vessel, nothing good could come from blazing a trail of destruction.

My expertise would focus on the diplomatic side: salvaging our relations with the victimized species. The choice, of how to respond to a personal and cowardly attack, belonged to the humans.

⋯ ✧ ⋯ ✧ ⋯

Chapter 88
Memory transcription subject:

Chief Hunter Isif,
Arxur Dominion Sector Fleet

Date [standardized human time]:
December 3, 2136

The Sol System underwent a serious overhaul, since my last visit. Earth’s defenses had been insufficient to ward off enemy vessels, and humanity wished to ensure such defeat never happened again. I marveled at the sheer manpower they must’ve dedicated to reconstruction.

According to my sensor data, the humans placed habitats as far out as the ‘Oort Cloud.’ It was impossible to spot the roughshod stations on the viewport. Their super-black paint absorbed almost all light, and their emissions were the only giveaway. A lesser mind might mistake the gravitational disturbances for an astronomical phenomenon.

I would assume the UN mimicked our cloaked stations, but they couldn’t have developed the technology so quickly. Terrans devised those blueprints on their own.

Humans detected my ship among the icy fragments, and nailed me with enough FTL-disruptors to fry an army. Nimble fighters raced out to join me, taking up flank positions. Visual contact confirmed to Terran scouts that the incoming vessel was of Arxur make, but that didn’t ease their suspicions. Perhaps they assumed the next Dominion visit wouldn’t be on friendly terms.

The Terran craft had me target-locked, and circled my ship with contemplative intent. Surely their generals realized that despite our solitary nature, our ships wouldn’t venture off alone to attack. My mission was diplomatic in nature; I was debating how thoroughly to betray my people. There was also the issue of the three Zurulians, who wouldn’t come out when I left drinking water. They must be dehydrated and delirious by now.

I hailed the cloaked habitat, hoping humanity wouldn’t make any rash decisions. It was unclear if they’d appreciate the tip-off, that their hideout wasn’t undetectable. An honest appraisal seemed helpful by my standards, but it could also wound Terran pride. That concept meant more to the Dominion than Elias Meier; however, Míngzé Zhao was not as even-keel.

“You are trespassing in the Sol system, but you know that already.” A female human with a dust-colored bowl cut appeared on screen. I recognized her as General Jones, the drone program’s lead. “To what do we owe the…pleasure?”

I bared my teeth. “Humans do not wish to continue open relations? Have you forgotten what we did for you so soon?”

“We didn’t expect the Arxur back here, keeping tabs on us. I know a warship when I see one, and I certainly don’t like it gunning for Earth. Why do you feel entitled to roam our home system?”

“Because I’m Chief Hunter Isif. You know, the single reason your species is still alive today. The one who gave you an army, sent food to your cities, pulled your dying from the rubble, and traded you the Venlil.”

“…I see. My nation thanked you, and housed you. That doesn’t mean you’re going to lord your aid over humanity forever. You must use proper diplomatic channels, like everyone else.”

“I’ve gone through your channels, and received a dismissive statement from Zhao. That’s unacceptable. I’ve earned some gratitude, if not respect.”

“What are you going to do, sue us?”

Malice glimmered in General Jones’ eyes, and a defiant smirk tugged at her lips. Fury swelled in my chest, threatening to spill into a roar. I was able to contain it to a growl, but I couldn’t believe what ingrates the humans were. The United Nations hadn’t been this flippant with me in the past, even after Meier’s death.

Why the sudden hostility? I came to help humanity, but now, I don’t know whether they deserve it.

Perhaps there was some truth to Shaza’s claim that the Terrans needed a kick in the teeth. If she took their bold-faced antagonism down a notch, that would be beneficial to my goals. Earth’s government warranted a reminder of their precarious position. I was less certain that I could rely on their leaders than ever.

Still, humans were the only predators who wanted to end sapient farming. Their lab-grown meat had the power to feed us, and to weaken Betterment’s grip on Arxur society. Terrans must see reason again, when I reminded them we were on the same side. Meier understood how I defended humanity, and kept Giznel off their back.

Concerns still hounded me over the three Zurulians, hiding on my ship. I’d risked my cover on impulse, and I couldn’t have them die after ferrying them here. It was worth brushing off the insult, so that my defective voice would settle down. However, I’d like to hear General Jones issue an apology, down the line. Her contemptful look was grating at my patience.

“I’m your only ally in the Dominion. The intelligence I can offer you is worth your time,” I hissed.

The primate cleared her throat. “You have something you want to share? Then spit it out.”

“I’ll only speak to Zhao. I rule this entire sector: your sector. I directly interact with our government, and keep them off your backs. I deserve to look my equal in the eye, yes?”

“Well, tough luck. The Secretary-General is unavailable.”

“Then so am I. You haven’t even forwarded the request to him. If your leader can’t spare a minute on a call, I can’t be bothered to share my thoughts.”

“I said he’s unavailable. I will apprise Zhao of any intel you divulge to us.”

“I want a personal chat, human! Are you fucking dense?”

Jones slanted her eyebrows. “How dare—”

“How dare YOU!” I roared. “If it was important…if I was Tarva, Zhao would make time. Hell, Tarva herself was more diplomatic than you people!”

The UN fighters still coasted alongside me, and I barely refrained from target-locking them. I was mistaken to think of humanity as a friend; they would always consider us second-class to the prey. The option to storm off, and communicate with Venlil Prime instead, grew more appealing by the minute. If the Terrans hadn’t disrupted my FTL capabilities, I would’ve left in a huff.

There was no logical reason the humans would confront an Arxur ally, and spit in his face. Perhaps their vengeance had driven them mad; it was clear they were obsessed with Sol’s military defenses. Another possibility was that this American general was superseding the chain of command. She could be seeking to claim my intel for her nation alone.

Was that it? Was Jones shutting Zhao out of the loop, as a power play? Coups weren’t unheard of, back when unrest plagued Wriss; rulers could change by the week.

The drone mastermind might resent that she was snubbed for Secretary-General, in favor of a general from a rival state. Undermining Zhao’s regime would fashion the Americans as an appealing alternative. The ostensible status was that humans quieted all clannish tendencies, under threat of extinction. The United Nations supposedly helped them work together against aliens. But I wasn’t sure Earth’s tribes had laid old grudges to rest.

General Jones tapped a few buttons, before sitting in silence for a minute. “Be careful what you wish for, Isif. The Secretary-General will speak with you.”

I was a bit relieved that the American-led forces hadn’t done anything rash. Humans were bold enough to try to capture me, and convince me to talk through other means. From what I read on my holopad, their interrogation methods could surpass even Arxur creativity. If I’d shared those tidbits with Giznel, he’d respect their cruelty.

A human male appeared on screen, dressed in formal attire. His skin was warm and tan, while his hair was styled as a black crew cut. Forehead wrinkles indicated he was middle-aged, likely with several decades in the service. Anger oozed from his taut grimace; even his shoulders were forward, asserting dominance.

“Mr. Secretary-General, it’s an honor.” I forced a placid expression, and dipped my head. “I intended for us to meet much sooner. A shame, yes?”

Zhao’s expression didn’t change. “Well, you have my full attention now. I suppose that is what you wanted.”

“It is? That American general was stalling me from contacting you. I fear she may be watching out for her national interests, at your world’s expense.”

“General Jones and I have an understanding. National interests mean nothing, with human interests under constant threat. That threat is extinction, and it pays no mind to borders. We cannot afford squabbles.”

“But Jones would not pass along my call.”

“Because I told her not to. I was already listening the entire time, you know.”

My eyes narrowed with outrage, and I lashed my tail. This Secretary-General would blow me off, when I came to Sol to protect his forces? For pack predators with ubiquitous empathy, they had a lousy way of showing it. Who was I kidding, to think humans would help defective Arxur? Dominion rebellion meant nothing to their self-oriented agenda.

I knew Terrans still cared about the Venlil, like their own pack. The new Secretary-General also lauded the other races that aided Earth, yet sported contempt for the Arxur. Furthermore, they launched new ‘exchange programs’ with the Yotul and Zurulians, while welcoming defecting herbivores to their alliance. The ever-patient humans found the resolve to train the quaking prey! To my amazement, those efforts were getting results.

Obligate carnivores just aren’t convenient to their new empire…is that it? Or maybe they cannot forgive our crimes…

I gritted my teeth. “What have I ever done to you? I helped you and asked nothing in return. I could’ve conquered Earth, but I treated you as equals.”

“That’s the only reason I haven’t ordered Jones to capture you, Isif,” Zhao said. “With what we know today, you’re no friend of humanity. Listen carefully and tell your boss; we are not supporting agendas that go against our interests.”

“What are you talking about? Our interests are the same!”

“We both know that’s not true. You were adamant about Fahl and Sillis being glassed, and humanity following your every command. We are not your puppets.”

“What? You’ve gone mad, Zhao. The Dominion knows you are weak, and they won’t tolerate your interference. I’m trying to keep weak predators alive into the future!”

“Weak? We are not weak. We are young, and growing exponentially.”

I hissed in exasperation. “Then give yourselves time to grow. Fahl and Sillis do not help your…human first agenda, am I right?”

“It’s about the principle of encouraging our enemies to surrender. Besides, if we forked over the Tilfish and the Harchen worlds without a fight, it would cement this ‘human weakness’ in your minds. I will not set that precedent. The Arxur shall respect us.”

Secretary-General Zhao cast an unwavering glare at the screen. As much as I wanted to unload on him, my departure from Sol required humanity lifting their FTL disruptors. Securing a ride out might require groveling; politeness was mandatory for my request to leave. But at this point, I had no intent of passing along Shaza’s plans to Earth.

It felt like a betrayal, that the UN would dismiss my high-risk friendship with humanity. How could Terrans say our interests weren’t aligned, unless they were unwilling to help us? I thought we both sought a better future, and a change in the Arxur government. My defective voice wanted the hominids to like me, and accept me as one of their peers.

A delirious scream echoed behind me, and my head whipped around. One of the Zurulians had climbed atop a table, in the camera’s backdrop. It was the one who’d been crying in the cage, though she looked worse for wear. Her lips were dry from dehydration, and her eyes were half-closed with fatigue. I could see desperation glitter in her pupils.

“H-human! Help us…p-please,” she croaked, in a ragged voice.

The Secretary-General leaned forward in his chair, and his eyes widened with alarm. His jaw clenched shortly after, as he recognized the Zurulian’s paltry condition. While I appreciated that Zhao loathed our cattle practices, the quadrupeds’ deterioration wasn’t my fault. I’d risked my hide to rescue them, and I had provided for them. Was I supposed to flush them out at gunpoint, to drink water?

“So that’s why there are four life signatures on your ship.” The Terran’s voice was low and charged with fury. I noticed his hands typing at a holopad, likely communicating with Jones’ forces. “You’re using our friends as bargaining chips? You’d commit acts of terrorism in the Sol System?!”

I shook my head. “It’s not like that! I brought them here so you could send them home.”

“Yeah, right; conveniently forgot to mention their presence, huh? Is that your food for this week? Filthy croc.”

“That’s it! I will fucking rip you from limb-to-limb, you puny branch-swinger! I will carve out your itsy-bitsy canines…and embed them on my armor as a prize!”

“You won’t be doing anything. I was planning to catch-and-release you, but you’re better taken out of the equation. The United Nations will be bringing you into custody, Isif.”

I tried to attempt evasive maneuvers, but the UN blew out my propulsions with a single hit. My weapons system was malfunctioning, and I found the glitch rather coincidental. The Terran fighters flanking me used mechanisms to latch on to my hull seamlessly. Sparks flew behind me, as humans began breaching into the cabin. The Zurulians bounded up to the noise, yipping for aid.

The world took on a red hue, and anger overflowed into my consciousness. Feeling the need to attack something, I swung my claws at my dashboard. Electricity arced through the air, as I tore a chunk of metal out of the pedestal. Adrenaline led me to blindly throw the debris, and it nearly landed atop the Zurulians. Realizing I’d almost harmed them snapped me back to lucidity, though I was still steaming.

Why is Zhao doing this? I was a valuable asset to him, from a logistical standpoint.

The Secretary-General leaned in to another holopad. “This is a high-value prisoner. Bring him in, alive! I want to know what he knows.”

“You’re making a mistake!” I roared. “Why are you doing this?!”

“For one, you’ve learned too much about Earth’s revamps. The element of surprise is important, if worse comes to worst. An enemy Chief Hunter can’t ruin that for us.”

“Enemy? Meier knew I’m not your enemy. We want the same fucking thing, Zhao.”

“Meier was naïve. He couldn’t see an enemy if they were holding him at gunpoint.”

I curled my lip with disdain. “You don’t believe I’m an ally, just because I’m an Arxur.”

“No, I don’t believe you’re an ally, because we’ve…obtained Arxur reports. Including Shaza’s partial transcript of your visit.”

I leaned back on my haunches. Understanding dawned on me, as I realized that the United Nations had tapped into our communications network. Meier understood how I played things up for effect, but that knowledge hadn’t been passed on to his successor. Perhaps my acting was a bit too superb, if it fooled the very people I was protecting.

My offense over Terran aggression was gone, once there was some basis for their behavior. This was all a misunderstanding; it should be easy for me to clear things up. Of course Earth wouldn’t welcome someone who claimed to be using them in a war. It didn’t help that I insulted Zhao in my speech, though such rhetoric was tailored for a different audience.

“What is it you think that I said?” I hissed.

“‘I’m using humans to make the Dominion the supreme, unchallenged power.’ Oh, what about this one? ‘The UN are clueless to our aims, because Zhao is blind and on the warpath.’”

“You can’t take that at face value. Read between the lines! You’re intelligent. I was trying to talk Shaza down…she wants to nuke your prizes, with your forces still there.”

“We know that. And we know your rationale against an attack was ‘Not yet, save our strength.’”

A metallic section of the wall toppled inward, and Terran soldiers stalked inside. The primates almost tripped over the Zurulians, who ran toward their entry point. The humans rounded on me in formation, wearing goggles over their eyes. After a moment’s hesitation, I sunk to my knees and raised my paws in surrender.

“Why would you tell me you know all this? You’re tipping your hand,” I growled.

The Secretary-General sported a malevolent grin. “Because you’re never going to tell your people any of it.”

A dart embedded itself in my neck, and I plucked it out on instinct. My head felt a bit woozy, before I lost my balance. The humans crept closer, readying more sedatives in case the dosage was inadequate. My eyes fluttered, and my vision shrank to a pinhole. There was no hope of talking my way out of this situation…and it wasn’t the Dominion who did me in like I imagined.

My undoing was assisting alien predators, who never planned for me to leave the Sol system again.

⋯ ✧ ⋯ ✧ ⋯

Chapter 96
Memory transcription subject:

Captain Sovlin,
United Nations Fleet Command

Date [standardized human time]:
December 5, 2136

To recount the harrowing hours after the initial clash would be a strenuous ordeal in itself. The Terrans’ intention was to turn this into a lengthy battle, one which could go on for days. It was gut-wrenching to see Arxur vessels, huddled around Sillis’ azure shape; I knew this was a facsimile of what the predators saw on Earth. There had never been a chance of holding or retaking the planet, not against a superior enemy.

The UN kept our forces active, while rotating personnel to keep fresh eyes on duty. Carlos and Onso were given leave for a short nap, though they were set to return within a few hours. Samantha was going through cups of brown liquid like it was a magic elixir, and Tyler had summoned a mug of his own. As a former officer, I understood his hesitancy to abandon his station.

I’m feeling a bit worn out myself. This is the longest battle I’ve ever witnessed…they’re supposed to end in the span of a few hours.

“Any update, Sovlin?” Tyler stifled a yawn, and shook his head to avert sleepiness. “Break down the Arxur’s current movement.”

I blinked my heavy eyelids. “Sir, the grays haven’t deviated from their orbital positions. They’re on high alert, since our fleet is utilizing these ‘hit-and-run’ tactics as you call them.”

“And the FTL disruptors are holding?”

“Yes, sir. UN ships are emitting that signal loud and clear, since we’re outside the reach of Sillis’ transmitters. Don’t want the bastards warping in right atop us, like we did to them.”

“Good. And Sovlin? You look like shit. Get some rest; I’ll have a tech cover for you.”

I disembarked from my seat, knowing that I wasn’t much of a tactical specialist with my current brain fog. The humans weren’t going to win this war by exhausting their crew; it wasn’t clear how long we could stay in a state of combat readiness. Even a predator would tire of stress-driven situations over an extended duration. My paws shuffled into the mess hall, and I collapsed on the cool floor.

Gojids certainly weren’t built for constant adrenaline. It was a matter of time before the humans’ efficacy diminished as well, and our resistance crumbled. Predators tired of a chase after awhile, which was why prey gained their flight impulse. When Carlos and Sam discussed their legends with Cilany, they left out their historical battles. I could fill in the blanks well enough from the Federation’s knowledge.

Tyler had discussed Earth’s world wars, though in limited detail. The first conflict was a particular display of primitive barbarism. Its trench warfare was either exaggerated, or had resulted in sloppy performances from their soldiers. The fact that it took so long to sue for peace was stubbornness; it was the refusal to surrender that Carlos mentioned. A human’s body and mind would break before their will.

I snoozed on the mess hall floor. My dreams were broken, bits of harsh memories sewn together. Tyler’s confirmation that humans fought wars for thousands of years looped through my head. My brain fused that encounter with Zarn’s initial briefing. The Takkan doctor had been emphatic, stating that Terrans tormented each other through constant battle.

“Humans are conquerors, who derive pleasure from dominating others. That is what their 'explorers' have always done on their homeworld. They are aggressive, brutal, and territorial,” Zarn’s voice declared.

Tyler hurling me into the cabinets resurfaced. “It’s just how we are, man.”

The imagery became increasingly surreal and chaotic, as my subconscious grasped at examples of their empathy. The humans had allowed a Gojid hospital ship to pass at the border skirmish; those pilots’ radio chatter had conveyed a desire to talk, not fight. Throughout that clash, their forces ignored the vulnerable colony and hammered our military outposts instead. Those weren’t the actions of out-of control brutes.

A calloused hand shook my shoulder, and I groaned as I stirred. The explorers on Venlil Prime hadn’t done what Zarn implied. First contact should’ve seen Tarva’s world conquered, when even Tyler acknowledged that invigorating drive. How could I understand mankind’s dichotomous nature, when the past and the present were contradictions? If I solved that riddle, it might give me an honest perspective on the Gojids’ monstrous side too.

“Sovlin, you can’t just sleep out here.” Carlos was hovering over me, and taking care to avoid my bristling spines. “We let you get a few hours of shut-eye, but…someone’s gonna step on you!”

I rubbed my eyes. “C-Carlos? Are humans, as a species, conquerors?”

“Er, I don’t think so. We’re warriors, and some people confuse the two. Mix in clannish tendencies and competition, then believe that your enemy is intrinsically different from you…yes, we felt that way toward our own. But look what the herbivores did to us because of that same belief.”

“You’re saying old humans didn’t see their enemies as people.”

“Yes. That’s the belief that makes monsters of us all. Nobody has empathy for someone that is too unalike.”

The pieces clicked in my brain, alongside a rush of horror. The Federation was guilty of the same savagery as the humans; they pillaged and condemned Earth, because predators weren’t people. Brutal capabilities didn’t just lurk inside primitive uplifts and flesh-eating species. Most concerningly, zero empathy wasn’t a requisite to complete atrocities beyond comprehension.

But it’s not just a trait of the Gojids. Thank the Protector.

“You’re very wise, Carlos,” I murmured. “I wonder where you learned it from.”

The olive-skinned soldier sighed. “Let’s just say I didn’t grow up in a stable home. There’s a reason I didn’t check in on my family post-Earth. I decided that I never wanted to be like my old man, and that I was going to figure things out for myself.”

“And you joined the Peacekeepers to get away?”

“Yes. I got assigned to humanitarian missions at first, and it felt good to make a difference. I learned a lot about people…er, humans. I learned how to stand in the other guy’s shoes.”

“Thank you for trying to understand me, from the beginning. I never deserved it.”

“I’m not so sure you’re a bad person. You had that belief I talked about, and it made you a monster. That’s as human as it gets, Sovlin.”

“I’m not sure that is a compliment.”

“Oh, it’s not. Anyhow, Tyler…ahem, Officer Cardona wants us back on the bridge. Let’s get to work, huh?”

Carlos ushered me back into the bridge, a rejuvenated light in his eyes. The situation on Sillis appeared unchanged, from a cursory glance at the viewport. Smaller Terran craft harassed the Arxur fringes, while the main UN fleet prevented escape or reinforcements. The grays weren’t challenging our position. It seemed that the demons wanted us to make the first move, while the humans were in no rush to act.

Captain Monahan had joined the brown liquid party, with a steaming cup in her hand. The commander was still supervising the bridge, and her puffy eyes suggested she hadn’t taken any reprieve. Our warship was playing a supporting role, poking at any Arxur that neared Terran ranks. Combat readiness was maintained on the bridge; if there was an opportune moment, we’d capitalize on it.

I strode up to a weary Tyler. “Sir! You wanted us back? Shit, I’m ready to tear the grays a new one!”

A rested Onso sauntered up to our group. “We’re in agreement there. When are we charging in?”

“We’re making plans,” the blond-haired human growled. “Listen to what we intercepted while you were out. The Arxur got a nice call through their, shall I say, poorly-hidden FTL comms.”

I peered at the sensors officer’s screen, and saw video clips from across the region. It was news to me that the Arxur possessed FTL communications; building such a network seemed beyond their intelligence. How had the Federation never detected this infrastructure, if it existed? Nonetheless, it was tough to argue with footage that couldn’t have reached us yet.

The first clip Tyler selected was from a probe encircling a military station. Massive hangars were visible from above, alongside a few patrollers circling lazily. Alarms sounded on the base, moments before sleek bombers blinked into existence. I could see the UN insignia emblazoned on their hulls, alongside other retrofits. The upgrades were apparent from what humanity’s allies first loaned them.

So this is why we weren’t given more numbers for the shadow fleet. The resources were diverted elsewhere, and not just to the war with the Federation.

The Terran bombers swooped down on the Dominion installation, just as they had assaulted Gojid bases. Enemy resistance was wiped out upon contact, unable to hold a candle to this raid. Munitions rained down on the martial station, and obliterated its defensive outfits first. Explosions punished the living quarters next; any filthy grays still onboard were buried.

The humans ensured that nothing remained of the base, and that no Arxur escaped off-world. It floored me that the grays had allocated so few ships to defense. Then again, the aggressive monsters couldn’t think of anything but killing. Their singular focus was inflicting torment upon the Tilfish homeworld. It had been a long time since the Arxur met a worthy foe.

Samantha swallowed a gulp of her bean drink. “It’s the same scene on every base we’re aware of. Even if these fuckwits take Sillis, they’ll have no place for the ships to return. Oh, and we snipped the cord on those comms too.”

I flicked my claws. “Nice work! You took the bastards for everything they’re worth.”

“We took something else of theirs too,” Tyler chuckled. “You’ll like this, Gojid.”

The tall human picked out a new video from the data feed. A Terran transport was docking with a streamlined station, which seemed tailored to ship traffic rather than war. More UN craft latched onto other compartments, rather than causing a traffic jam in the main hangar. The primates were well-practiced at forced entries; they’d make an opening or pick a lock where necessary.

Tyler jumped to an internal security feed, which showed armored humans busting through an emergency airlock. Fattened Arxur guards greeted them with gunfire, but the Terrans overran their garrison. The boarding party mowed down their opposition, and barked to each other about rescuing captives. Several primates returned past the camera, carrying prey aliens that were in poor condition.

“We’ve had the plans to liberate the cattle farms since day one. Now that we know how the grays operate…we fucking hit every farm too,” Samantha hissed.

Carlos bared his teeth. “Our estimates are millions of cattle per sector. How are we going to get them all off-world?”

“They’re in our custody, and that’s what matters.” Tyler suppressed a yawn, and blinked with drowsiness. “We’ll move as many as we can.”

“That’s one hell of a…humanitarian victory, Carlos. Forget the logistics,” I said.

Onso curled his lip. “Why aren’t the grays going back for their assets?”

“Because that ship has sailed, buddy,” Tyler answered. “They threw the whole sector for one rock! Might as well take Sillis; they have nothing to lose.”

Satisfaction swelled in my chest, and the Yotul brightened with content as well. The Arxur just lost all major assets and infrastructure across a 100-light year radius; this could be a pivotal turning point in the war. While the humans had sacrificed Sillis, they had undermined the grays’ malice everywhere else. This was cause for celebration, no matter what unfolded in this system.

“I’d love to see the predators losing their dimwitted minds,” I chuckled.

Samantha folded her arms. “Would you? Show him what they directed at us.”

Tyler brought up a single outbound transmission, and the visage of a female gray materialized. It was the same one taunting the humans at the start of the battle. Now, its maw was agape with fury; its eyes were furious slits. It jabbed its claws at the camera, like it wished to stab the listener through the screen.

“You irreverent grass-munchers really fucked up now! How dare you destroy Dominion assets?! I’m going to burn this fucking planet to the ground,” the raving Arxur roared. “Since you killed my food, I’m going to make a cattle farm solely of humans to replace it! That will put you back in your fucking place! You will regret this.”

I blinked in confusion. The grays perceived the humans as equals, and that should be doubly true after our battlefield prowess here. From what I’d overheard, it would go against the Arxur’s twisted philosophy to eat another predator. Was this Chief Hunter really going to go against its government’s stance, out of spite?

I don’t think the humans would make good cattle. They’re too headstrong and devious.

Tyler cleared his throat. “That leads us to our plan. Evacuations on Sillis were subpar, given their rushed timetable. We will, in no circumstances, stand for humans being captured for that purpose.”

“So what are we doing? Shooting down cattle ships?” I offered.

“If it comes to that and we can’t board them, yes. But getting soldiers off Sillis just became a priority. The UN fleet is going to engage the Arxur head-on, distract ‘em. Meanwhile, shuttles will sneak through the gaps and rescue as many humans as possible.”

“Great, sir. Just tell me how we’re going to get their attention.”

“That’s the thing. I…I will be heading down to the surface. I know it’s atypical for an officer to volunteer himself, but a personal matter has come up that I must attend to.”

Onso hissed in annoyance. “You didn’t invite me? Where was the signup sheet?”

“You can come if you want to. But buddy, it’s very dangerous.”

“Dangerous for them. I’m coming with you, end of discussion.”

That was an interesting way of speaking to a superior officer, but the Yotul seemed to get special considerations. I couldn’t understand why Tyler would rush off and shirk his station duties. It was an unusual decision to say the least. What could be personal enough to have swayed his judgment? While I didn’t want to challenge the big guy, I felt a responsibility to talk some sense into him.

“Forgive my insolence, but I care about your welfare. You’re an officer, sir, like you said!” I chewed at my claws, anxious at the risk Tyler was undertaking. “With respect, you’re more useful up here. The captain wouldn’t want you wasting your talents on fieldwork.”

“Captain Monahan has been apprised of the circumstances, and she signed off on my departure,” the sensors officer rumbled. “With this development, I would be too distracted to fulfill my duties. You guys will be fine without me.”

“What development? Personal or not, I can’t understand without a clue why you’re doing this.”

Samantha grimaced. “We should just tell Sovlin, sir. He’ll find out on his own.”

Tyler narrowed his eyes. “Suit yourself. The floor is all yours, Sammy.”

“It’s Sam. Anyway, snap to it, Sovlin. I was scanning transmissions from the surface, like Ty ordered, and I keyed into this one.”

Samantha’s pale fingers scrolled through her viewing history, and she picked out a highlighted transmission. I eyed the humans warily, wondering why they had reservations about sharing this information. What could happen on Sillis that had any personal impact on myself? The Tilfish genocide was tragic, but I had no connections on the surface.

A broken audio clip filtered through the speakers. “This is Captain Marcel Fraser…”

Hot blood rushed to my ears, and a ringing sound drowned out the rest of the transmission. I keeled over against the station, shaking my head in denial. That predator’s voice was one I could recognize anywhere. Knowing that Marcel, the human I’d tormented, was trapped on Sillis changed everything. Of course Tyler wanted to rush off and rescue his packmate.

What would Marcel think of my presence on this ship? What if Slanek is with him…I threw that poor Venlil around like a rag doll.

Guilt ebbed through my veins with renewed strength. How was it fair that I was cozy on this ship, while Marcel and Slanek could be captured to a cattle farm? If there was a way for me to trade places, I would do it in a heartbeat. It wouldn’t scratch the debt I owed my two victims. I deserved suffering from the beginning anyways; the Terrans were too merciful.

Tyler twisted his fingers into my scruff. “Sovlin? Shit, this is why I didn’t want to tell him.”

“I..I can’t…” Tears soaked my cheek fur, and mucus congested my nasal passageways. “G-good luck, sir. I understand.”

“Hey, I’m gonna get Marcel and Slanek out of there. Just need to pull someone off nav station to fly my shuttle. I know those folks are a lot harder to replace than us people reading screens. Not sure we can spare a pilot, but I have to get to Sillis.”

“I’ll g-go. I can fly.”

“No way! How the fuck would I explain that to Marcel and Slanek?”

“I’ve flown d-down during an orbital raid before. Back when I picked up Cilany. Carlos and Sam can attest to my skills. It’s t-the best option for the ship…sir.”

“I…I don’t think they’ll react well to your presence. You know what I mean.”

“Slanek and Marcel are both pilots. If either wishes to serve me to the grays, I will crawl into their cages willingly. I just need to get you down there. Let me do this for them…for Marcel.”

Tyler crossed his arms, deliberating his options. I understood that my victims wouldn’t be pleased to see me, but taking a pilot from navigations could get humans here killed. It had to be an expendable crew member like myself. Besides, from my perspective, failure was not an option. Marcel and Slanek would be saved, if I had to sacrifice myself in the process.

“Fine,” the sensors officer decided. “Let’s get a shuttle and get moving.”

⋯ ✧ ⋯ ✧ ⋯

Chapter 108
Memory transcription subject: Chief Hunter Isif

Isif,
Chief Hunter of the Arxur Dominion Sector Fleet

Date [standardized human time]:
December 13, 2136

My shuttle traversed the space that separated me from my alien pen pal. The eight thousand Dominion ships I'd summoned had arrived as well; those were the assets I had within immediate range of the Dossur homeworld. The Arxur fleet awaited my command, requiring further instruction as to our goal.

The reason why they hesitated was simple; the Federation had numerical strength that seemed fantastical. The Kolshians had sent forty thousand ships barreling into the system, or possibly more. It was greater than the initial size of Kalsim's extermination fleet! I understood what Prophet-Descendant Giznel had implied about the prey powers being able to muster up numbers, if they wanted to.

The invasion of Mileau's system involved an overwhelming show of force, per my initial readings. The more I performed the mental math, it was striking how easy these numbers would be for their assembly. With a mere 30 species having flipped to humanity's side, that left 270 races to pull resources and ships from. If all of those races contributed 140 ships, that gave the number we saw today.

It's a mere fraction of their available resources to pull from. This is the tip of the iceberg for the Kolshians' might.

The Dossur's defenses were steamrolled by the juggernaut armada, and the human ships seeking repairs didn't hold a candle to this astronomical force. General Jones was off her hunting pedestal if she thought I could stop this assault! Even our numbers were unlikely to achieve more, beyond delaying the Federation's end goals. But since I was already here, risking my cover, there had to be an attempt to rescue Felra.

"Felra is in an 'old Federation spot.' A space station, which has a separate area for humans awaiting repairs," I muttered to myself.

I was grateful that my shuttle had no company, so I could muse over how to locate her aloud. The Arxur ships around me grew restless, now that I was in the system. They expected orders from their Chief Hunter soon, and it was a matter of time before the UN or the Federation noticed our arrival too. Was it my sentimentality that was telling me to interfere?

My viewport zoomed in on Mileau. The Dossur homeworld wasn't reflecting any antimatter damage; the Kolshians had the planet comfortably under control. After the Federation failed to subdue the Mazics, they'd ramped up their efforts. I could see the enemy sending shuttles down to Mileau's surface, and realized that their goals were likely re-education.

"All Arxur ships, listen up. We are here at the request of the United Nations, who have the means to feed all of us forever," I barked into the Dominion's encrypted feed. "Some of you were there on Earth, and you remember how well-fed you were. For that reason, I expect your hunting efforts to avoid Terran-affiliated races; we know it will be worth the pittance of restraint. Now engage with the Federation attackers, at once!"

Our ships surged forth out of various gravity wells, swarming the handful of attackers allocated to outer stations. I was bent over my holopad, and scrolling through a poorly-secured military personnel database. Inspectors were considered part of the space force on Mileau, as far as I remembered. That meant I could figure out which outpost Felra was assigned to.

Plasma munitions flashed across the void, and the element of surprise allowed us to pick off any stragglers. Dossur defenders, complemented by an array of UN ships, seemed to pause their desperate efforts. There weren't many "friendlies" left within the system, but the survivors seemed baffled by the Arxur's arrival. Perhaps they thought our onslaught was an inopportune coincidence.

"Attention, military personnel of the Dossur home system." I broadcasted my next message onto an open channel, and tried to eliminate any hostile words. "The Arxur are here, at the behest of the United Nations, to aid you in defending your claim against the Federation. I will only warn you once: do not fire upon us."

My pupils darted back to the screen, where I'd searched up Felra's file. The rodent's likeness was unmistakable in her documentation, and her present assignment was listed near the top. I searched up the space station number, pinning it down on a star chart. The rest of the battle faded away, as I raced to pull up that location on the viewport.

The complex was nestled within an asteroid belt, which separated the inner and outer planets. A few dozen Federation attackers had tamed its meek defenses, and docked with the station to capture their inhabitants. The energy readings in the vicinity were fresh, suggesting that the Kolshians only put down spiteful (human) resistance in the past hour.

There might still be time to save the Dossur, if you hurry.

I hurled the maximum output into my thrusters, and my shuttle blazed a path for Felra's station. A few Arxur vessels tailed their commander, though I figured they were baffled by a Chief Hunter leading the charge. This entire mission was going to raise questions I couldn't answer. Right now, I didn't have the time to waste on tact.

The Federation vessels pulled away from the station, and met us for a head-on confrontation. I shirked the engagement altogether, leaving my underlings to duke it out with the prey. The sudden courage from the Kolshians surprised me; it was clear they were more competent than they let on. My eyes swelled with franticness, searching for an open docking port.

"There are none!" I hissed to myself. "NONE! I don't have time for a proper breaching action...I have to get down there. For fuck's sake, I'll make an opening."

Scanning the station's blueprints, I identified a maintenance tunnel, which should be well-clear of any living quarters. This shuttle carried two missiles, and I hoped the use of one would only demolish a wall. While station operators could seal off individual compartments, that also meant that I'd need a pressurized suit for oxygen. I tugged the emergency fabric on with haste, before donning a safety harness.

With my biological requirements taken care of, I fired a missile into the station's exterior wall. The tunnel was exposed to the vacuum of space, its structure blasted wide open. Bullets clipped my rear flank, as Federation hostiles noticed my approach. Curses spewed from my maw, and I wrenched the steering column toward the new gap.

The shuttle closed in on the Dossur space station, dodging enemy munitions. I held no interest in returning fire; that would increase the amount of time it took to reach Felra. My ship's nose dove through the opening, and I twisted the vessel's body to skid along the floor. Friction resulted in both an awful screech and shuddering sensation, before the tail slammed against a half-intact wall.

My shoulder ached from the harness' restraint, but I unclipped it without waiting. My suited paws tucked a firearm into a holster, and I slunk out into the station. The night backdrop of space was visible through the gap, as well as distant exchanges of munitions. Suffocating Kolshians and other Federation aliens lie gasping for air, alongside two Terran soldiers.

I grabbed one human in each paw, and dragged them toward the section divider. The primates were lethargic and their expressions were locked in an empty display; there was nothing behind their eyes, with no oxygen coming to the brain. I opened the emergency compartment, throwing the weaker predators inside. Sealing the hatch behind me, I removed my oxygen helmet. The Terrans' skin had been turning blue, though they were rapidly regaining normal coloration now.

"Hi." I swished my tail as politely as I could, and allowed the humans a moment to breathe. "Chief Hunter Isif, at your service. Sorry about the...unforeseeable depressurization. What are your names?"

One primate began reaching for her service weapon, and I hissed in irritation. My gun was out of its holster in a second, pointed at her in warning. Her hand remained frozen in place for a long second, before she submitted to my threat. I bared my teeth, a formidable warning rather than amusement.

My tongue flitted between my teeth. "Ah, you guys look like fresh reinforcements. Let me guess—the United Nations sent you from Fahl, right across the border? You never saw direct action, since Shaza's...plan for a swift takeover of Sillis was a failure."

"Go to hell," the female coughed.

"So I was right, I take it. I'm here as an ally. Where are the Dossur civilians? I promise, I'm here to get them out, not to harm them."

"Everybody knows your idea of getting them out is a cattle farm." The other human sat up, pulling a broken glass instrument off his eyes. "What are you really up to? Claiming this system for yourself, or making—"

"STUPID! I'm a spy for the United Nations, a piss-poor one. That is what I'm up to, you and your government's stupid ideas. I have been...personally motivated into offering assistance."

"A spy, huh? Of course, you're the one from Earth. They had every opportunity to take you to Area 51 or some clandestine facility..."

The female cursed in exasperation. "Are you kidding me, Olek? You just instantly believe the UN has Arxur spies, with zero proof."

"Do you honestly think I would craft such a story on my own? Saying such a thing aloud is going to get me killed. I have no time to persuade you, humans, so tell me where the Dossur are now!" I roared.

Olek tilted his head. "Good argument, props to you, man. They've been ordered to lock themselves in their quarters. Big sign, says, 'Personal Quarters.' Just keep going straight, can't miss it."

"Thank you. Was that so hard?!"

Grumbling to myself, I stomped off past the corridor's hatch. The Terran soldiers struggled to their feet, and I resigned myself to them following me like herdless Venlil. Arrogance aside, I could use backup if I encountered Federation resistance. The herbivores might lack skill in combat, but they could team up on me alone.

Humans are competent fighters, so it's not like they're dead weight. That said, this Olek guy seemed a little too willing to believe that I'm a spy...

Olek squinted, without the glass adornment by his eyes. I hoped the human hadn't lost his vision altogether; even if he could only see shapes, I was certain that he was more competent than the Kolshians. The female human, who I believed Olek had called Lisa in whispers, was staring at me with distrusting, bloodshot eyes. Perhaps the duo were following me to ensure that I wasn't rounding up any Dossur.

I scanned the perimeter for hostiles. "How has your military experience been going?"

"This was supposed to be a relaxing assignment, after watching the Harchen for weeks," Lisa complained. "We were shipped here just in case, and the second we kick our boots off, in they come. Now the Arxur are here, telling fantastical stories that sound like Olek crafted them!"

Olek cleared his throat. "They hit all of our allies with a test invasion. I hope it's not like this everywhere...I've grown attached to some friends on Venlil Prime."

"My source says this is the primary target. Venlil Prime is fine," I replied.

"That's a relief. Say, Isif the alleged secret agent, what convinced you to come here? You should tell us, since we're a team."

"We're not a team."

"C'mon, you totally want to tell me!"

I've already told these two humans everything, just to get Felra's location. They might as well know the truth, if they're stalking me. They're going to notice that I know her.

"An internet chatting service. A...a Dossur is my best friend," I growled.

Lisa's eyebrows furrowed. "What?! I'd hardly believe you'd dare to make a story like that up."

"I would not. Because it's insane."

I scanned my visual translator over the text markings overhead, and it deciphered the Dossur language as directions with arrows. Just as Olek had promised, the crew quarters were located down the main corridor. The passage had been devoid of confrontation, but gunfire echoed from up ahead. That meant Federation soldiers had already reached the living areas.

The Kolshians must've sent forces down from two angles; one boarding party had been held in the maintenance tunnel that I detonated. The other likely attacked from the other side, charging straight from the hangar bay to the quarters. Splitting up human defenders was rather tactical, for a species that didn't know the meaning of offense. Allegedly...

"Which one is your supposed pal?" Lisa pointed to a piece of paper, which I assumed contained room assignments. "Also, I see a few dozen Kolshians and count three of us. Maybe we should rethink our strategy."

The prototype visual translator had no trouble with the roll call, which listed Felra as room 219. I committed the Dossur symbols for that number to memory, knowing her life depended on it. My firearm wavered in my paws, and I dropped into a hunting crouch. The humans crept along as well, lining up enemies in their scopes.

My pupils scanned each door for the numbers, while I ensured that my steps were silent. I could see cerulean and violet Kolshians moving between rooms, and exiting with sedated Dossur. All I could hope was that Felra wasn't among those already captured; it would be next-to-impossible to spring her from the Federation re-education party. My gaze drifted several doors down the hall, one room past where the Kolshians were now.

I pointed with a claw. "That one!"

My whisper was almost inaudible, but the humans understood the message. These Terrans were rather cooperative; I wondered if it was since they could gang up on me, the second I made a move or was found to be deceitful. The primates often had a strange way of showing gratitude for saving their lives. I'd hauled their oxygen-deprived bodies from the tunnel, yet they were likely calculating ways to kill me.

I can respect it at least. Unless I try to backstab them, I doubt they'll try anything stupid. Fighting the Federation is enough for now.

Right now, the three of us needed to get past the Kolshian posse; the enemy soldiers stood between us and Felra's door. The thought crossed my mind to use the Terrans as a distraction, but I knew they'd see right through such suggestions. How were we going to reach my Dossur friend without alerting the invaders? A firefight seemed like the only solution, so I gestured for us to charge.

My claw depressed the trigger, and I nailed two Kolshians in the back before they could react. Olek and Lisa joined in on my fire, peppering any soldiers that couldn't find cover. The Federation got their bearings in a second, and hurled bullets back in our direction. We dropped down closer to the floor, crawling closer to Felra's door.

Most hostiles had ducked inside the room they were currently raiding, but a few had moved onto the next quarters: room 219. I scurried past the first door, feeling static electricity as a bullet whizzed over my spine. Lisa offered suppressing fire, as a visually-impaired Olek scrambled after me. The Federation had gotten to the target ahead of us, but I couldn't stop.

I fired desperate shots at the advancing soldiers. "No! NO! We're too close to let anything happen."

Panic clamped at my heart, seeing four Kolshians kicking down Felra's door. I could hear a shrill scream, which lacked power or grit. Adrenaline flowed through my veins, alongside a deeper emotion of concern. I rounded the doorway in a fluid motion, and used my nostrils to pounce at a Federation lackey.

My body was acting on pure autopilot, as I tore one soldier's throat on instinct. Felra's screams intensified, which encouraged my frenzy. If I was lucid, I would've realized she was shrieking because of my presence. However, in my haze, all I could see was two Kolshians cornering her; another was tracking the rodent's movements from further back.

My tail swept across the floor, earning a sickening crack as it broke two Kolshians' ankles in one swoop. The enemy tracker turned his gun muzzle toward me, and I punched out a fist on instinct. My appendage connected with bones, while the scent of blood hit my nostrils. Vision sharpened, as the scent made my eyes dilate.

I'd just shattered the Kolshian's windpipe and spine, with a single punch. The duo with the broken legs started to move, but Olek rushed in to stop them from engaging. It was tempting to finish the helpless Kolshians off; however, enough of my awareness had returned to realize it'd sicken Felra. I strained to bottle the adrenaline, drawing ragged gasps.

"H-help...human!" the Dossur managed to cry. "A...uh...arxur."

Olek's eyes narrowed with suspicion. "I thought you said she was your friend?"

"Hrrr." I grunted, struggling to formulate coherent words. The blood was still rushing in my ears, causing my claws to twitch. "It's complicated, is it not, Felra?"

"W-wha...h-how d-d-do...no."

Additional horror lit up the Dossur's gaze, as her terrified brain arrived at the truth. Something told me that she'd placed a name to the Arxur, who was towering over her with a maniacal snarl. I possessed a keen awareness of the blood slathered across my claws, and every scar and tooth fracture I had. The human watched from the sidelines, discerning enough of the subtext.

Felra swayed on her feet. "S-s-siffy?"

"Yeah."

The Dossur's eyes widened further than should be possible, and she passed out onto the floor.

⋯ ✧ ⋯ ✧ ⋯